<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- PQ_Text_EN -->
<!-- Author: 71891 -->
<!-- DateCreated: 5/3/2025 9:25:08 AM -->
<GameData>
		<BaseGameText>
			<!-- Ingame Text-->
			<Row Tag="LOC_MODIFIER_PQ_UNIT_STRENGTH_WITH_PROPERTY_DESCRIPTION">
				<Text>{Property} Gains 10 strength for each era</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_PQ_CHIYOCHICHI_DESCRIPTION">
				<Text>Santa Claus who was sponsored by the nation</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_KOUKOU_BESSOU_SCIENCE">
				<Text>+{1_num} [ICON_Science] Science from the adjacent Summer House</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_ENTERTAINMENT_SCIENCE">
				<Text>+{1_num} [ICON_Science] Science from the adjacent Entertainment Complex</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_THEATER_SCIENCE">
				<Text>+{1_num} [ICON_Science] Science from the Theater Square</Text>
			</Row>

			

			<!-- Civilopedia -->
			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_PQ_AZUMANGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
				<Text>"Azumanga Daioh" is a four-panel manga series created by Japanese manga artist Kiyohiko Azuma. It was first serialized in 1999 in the magazine *Monthly Comic Dengeki Daioh*. Its refreshing, humorous portrayal of everyday school life has made it a pioneering classic of the "slice-of-life" genre.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_PQ_AZUMANGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
				<Text>Set in a fictional Japanese high school, the story follows a group of uniquely charming female students and their daily antics over the course of three school years. The main characters include child prodigy Chiyo Mihama, the whimsical Ayumu "Osaka" Kasuga, the cool but soft-hearted Sakaki, the energetic troublemaker Tomo Takino, the calm and rational Koyomi Mizuhara, and the athletic latecomer Kagura.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_PQ_AZUMANGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
				<Text>Told in a four-panel format, the series presents everyday moments in a light and fragmented way, yet manages to weave a cohesive narrative of growth and friendship. Its gentle pacing, dialogue-driven humor, and contrasting character quirks create a warm yet hilariously endearing atmosphere.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_PQ_AZUMANGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
				<Text>The manga was adapted into a 26-episode anime series in 2002, produced by J.C.STAFF. Faithful to the original, the anime enhanced character interactions through thoughtful pacing and music, earning widespread acclaim and solidifying its status as a classic of the slice-of-life anime genre.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_PQ_AZUMANGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
				<Text>Beyond the anime, "Azumanga Daioh" inspired a wide range of derivative works, including drama CDs, art books, character songs, light novels, and the Game Boy Advance title *Azumanga Daioh Advance*, all of which are beloved by fans.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_PQ_AZUMANGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
				<Text>The artistic style and pacing of the series have had a significant influence on later slice-of-life works such as *K-On!*, *Lucky Star*, and *Nichijou*. Its sensitive portrayal of character psychology and authentic rhythm of everyday life helped shift four-panel manga from pure comedy to emotional resonance.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_PQ_AZUMANGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
				<Text>Though "Azumanga Daioh" concluded in 2002, its spirit and stylistic legacy continue to shape the world of manga and anime. It remains one of the foundational titles of school ensemble and slice-of-life storytelling, often hailed as a golden standard of the genre.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_PQ_CREATOR">
				<Text>Manga Artist</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_AZU_CREATOR">
				<Text>Kiyohiko Azuma</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_PQ_BASED">
				<Text>Mod Content Based</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_AZU_BASED">
				<Text>Azumanga Daioh: The Animation</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_PQ_MUSIC">
				<Text>Music</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_AZU_MUSIC">
				<Text>KURICORDER QUARTET</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_PQ_DECLARATION">
				<Text>Disclaimer</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_AZU_DECLARATION">
				<Text>
					This mod is a non-profit fan-made project, created for community-sharing purposes only. All visual/audio materials related to Azumanga Daioh anime are the property of their original rights holders.
					If any content in this mod infringes upon intellectual property rights, please contact me. I will promptly remove disputed materials upon formal request.
				</Text>
			</Row>
			
			
			
			<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_PQ_OSAKA_QUOTE">
				<Text>Saata Andagi~</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_PQ_OSAKA_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
				<Text>Ayumu Kasuga may always be a step behind, but without a doubt, her uniqueness will lead her into a world of her own - one filled with boundless imagination and infinite possibilities.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_PQ_OSAKA_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
				<Text>With the synergy of High School and Summer House, the laid-back joy of Azumanga Daioh brings significant advantages in [ICON_Amenities] Amenities, [ICON_Science] Science, and [ICON_Culture] Culture. If Ayumu Kasuga can tune into the rhythm of her whimsical daydreams - anarchy, then whether it's her identity as "Osaka" or her sudden bursts of insight, she may find the path that truly suits her.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_PQ_OSAKA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
				<Text>Ayumu Kasuga, better known as "Osaka", is one of the most beloved characters in *Azumanga Daioh*. Hailing from Japan's Kansai region, she was nicknamed "Osaka" by her classmates after transferring to their school, even though she was actually born in Wakayama Prefecture. Her speech often ends with the Kansai dialect particle "ya", adding to her distinctive charm. Osaka is easygoing and unhurried, often appearing spaced out - yet her thoughts are drifting through wild, imaginative realms, pondering things that may seem trivial to others. She sees the world through her own unique lens, though it's not always easy for others to understand her perspective.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_PQ_OSAKA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
				<Text>Though Osaka isn't particularly strong in academics or sports, she possesses a unique talent - riddles. Her vivid imagination and unconventional thinking make her surprisingly good at solving them. She also has 2.0 vision, a trait that reflects her sharp observational skills. Osaka is closest to Chiyo, with whom she often plays, chats, and shares thoughts and amusing experiences. Her quirky personality and behavior may sometimes confuse others, but it's exactly this uniqueness that makes her an indispensable part of the story and a fan favorite.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_PQ_OSAKA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
				<Text>Outside the story, Osaka enjoys tremendous popularity. She was the runner-up in Japan's 2002 "Saimoe" (Most Moe) tournament, a testament to her place in fans' hearts. She also appears as an adult teacher in the author's later work *Yotsuba&!*, offering a glimpse of her grown-up self. Her character has inspired countless fan creations, including games and books centered on her as the protagonist, further cementing her status as an enduring icon.</Text>
			</Row>


			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_PQ_CHIYOCHICHI_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
				<Text>Chiyo-chichi is a mysterious being who resembles a yellow cat but claims to be the biological father of Chiyo Mihama. He never appears in reality, instead showing up repeatedly in the dreams of Sakaki and Osaka. Despite his perpetually blank expression and open mouth, he displays a surprising capacity for speech - occasionally speaking in oddly accented English that leaves dreamers utterly baffled.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_PQ_CHIYOCHICHI_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
				<Text>Chiyo-chichi is highly emotional, prone to sudden outbursts of rage over seemingly trivial remarks. When angry, he trembles violently and changes color, exhibiting surreal and incomprehensible behavior. He harbors a deep aversion to the color red—especially tomatoes - yet obsessively insists Chiyo eat them for the sake of her health. As a symbolic "father" figure within dreams, he alternates between showing affection and behaving in ways that are bizarre or even unsettling.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_PQ_CHIYOCHICHI_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
				<Text>Though he claims to be Chiyo's father, his true identity is never confirmed. In both the anime and manga, Chiyo's real parents are never shown, suggesting that Chiyo-chichi may be a construct of Sakaki and Osaka's imaginations—an embodiment of the emotional void left by the absence of visible parental figures. At one point, he tells Sakaki she must "go find the real cat", a line that hints at a degree of self-awareness, though he denies ever saying it when awake.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_PQ_CHIYOCHICHI_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
				<Text>He frequently reappears in Sakaki and Osaka's dreams, sometimes as a friendly elder, other times as a cryptic prophet. He has even played roles akin to Santa Claus or a life advisor. While absurd and surreal, Chiyo-chichi holds deeper symbolic meaning, serving as one of Azumanga Daioh's most memorable representations of the blend between fantasy and reality, innocence and absurdity.</Text>
			</Row>


			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_PQ_KOUKOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
				<Text>The story of *Azumanga Daioh* primarily takes place at an unnamed ordinary Japanese high school. With its spacious, peaceful campus and open, relaxed atmosphere, the school serves as a vibrant stage full of youthful energy and everyday charm.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_PQ_KOUKOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
				<Text>Two key characters serve as teachers for the main class: Yukari Tanizaki, a young and wildly unpredictable English teacher, and Minamo Kurosawa (nicknamed "Nyamo"), a calm and composed P.E. instructor. Despite their contrasting personalities, the two are longtime friends whose quirky interactions often steal the spotlight.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_PQ_KOUKOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
				<Text>The school hosts a variety of traditional annual events, including the cultural festival and the sports day. During the cultural festival, students organize booths and performances by class, showcasing creativity and teamwork. Sports day is a lively athletic competition filled with spirited class rivalries and cheerful energy.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_PQ_KOUKOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
				<Text>Students also go on school trips, visiting places like Okinawa for sightseeing and learning, often leading to lighthearted and memorable incidents. Summer and winter breaks provide time for outdoor activities and deepening friendships, such as vacationing at Chiyo's summer house.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_PQ_KOUKOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
				<Text>Though the school itself has no special features or magical elements, it is the setting for the characters' growth, bonds, and shared memories - making it the emotional heart of the story and a symbolic setting within the slice-of-life school genre.</Text>
			</Row>


			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_PQ_BESSOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
				<Text>Chiyo Mihama's summer house, located by the seaside, is a key setting that appears multiple times in *Azumanga Daioh*. Spacious and luxurious with beautiful surroundings, the house serves as Chiyo's private vacation home and often becomes the backdrop for summer gatherings with her friends and teachers—moments filled with laughter and absurdity.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_PQ_BESSOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
				<Text>During the summer break of their first year, Chiyo invites Osaka, Tomo, Yomi, Sakaki, and teachers Yukari and Kurosawa to her summer house for the first time. On the way there, Yukari's reckless driving leaves Chiyo and Osaka visibly shaken. There, they enjoy classic summer activities like watermelon splitting and fireworks, while Osaka adds a bizarre twist by telling a spooky story that's more confusing than scary, creating a comically eerie atmosphere.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_PQ_BESSOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
				<Text>In their second-year summer trip, Kagura joins for the first time. Upon arrival, Tomo pranks the group by tossing the key into the grass, prompting a frantic group search. That night, everyone attends a nearby summer festival where Chiyo and Sakaki show off their yukata. Kurosawa gets drunk after being served alcohol by Yukari and Tomo, leading to wild behavior and unexpected revelations about her romantic past - leaving the students baffled and amused.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_PQ_BESSOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
				<Text>For their final trip in their third year, Kaorin joins the group. Like Chiyo, she is terrified by Yukari's driving. Although this trip is meant for studying for university entrance exams, it's still filled with chaos: Tomo keeps others awake at night, Osaka wakes Yukari with a kitchen knife in hand, and everyone ends up doing morning radio exercises. Additional episodes show them catching cicadas, playing volleyball, and stargazing - touching yet hilarious moments that reflect their bond.</Text>
			</Row>

			<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_PQ_BESSOU_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
				<Text>Though the exact location of Chiyo's summer house is never specified, it represents the cherished moments of youth and friendship. It is one of the characters' most relaxed and authentic spaces, and remains one of the most beloved and nostalgic settings in *Azumanga Daioh*.</Text>
			</Row>
		</BaseGameText>
</GameData>
